Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1869-1931 (inclusive), 1883-1927 (bulk) JL001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Pacific Improvement Company Records,
Bulk, 1883-1927
1869-1931
JL001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
180.0 Linear feet
Pacific Improvement Company.
Materials withdrawn from the collection
Duplicates; cancelled checks of the Carbon Hill Coal Company.
Scope and Content
The collection is made up of approximately fifty percent loose material and fifty percent bound volumes (percentage estimated in shelf space). The loose material consists of documents, both routine business and legal, correspondence, reports, minutes, various types of financial business, and maps and blueprints. Many of the subsidiary companies represented in these papers are not present in the series of bound material, and this loose material is dated, on an average, earlier than the volumes. The Louisville, New Orleans and Texas Railway Company, which does not appear in the bound material, is involved in much of the earlier, loose material, and of particular interest are the business papers of the various railroad lines which consolidated to form this line. They consist of agreements and correspondence in particular, which presents a rather complete picture of the growth of railroads late in the nineteenth century. A railroad in Guatemala also illustrates an interesting aspect of the company's activity.
Of interest to Californians should be the rather extensive collection of business records and correspondence related to the Monterey Peninsula, i.e. the Hotel Del Monte, Pacific Grove real estate, and the street railway in San Francisco, the Geary Street Park and Ocean Railway Company.
A great bulk of this loose material consists of routine correspondence, which fills forty-five large boxes. It is dated from 1901 to 1927, and only the Pacific Improvement Company itself is directly involved, as all the letters are either directed to or written by the directors of that company. The letters are in regard to, however, the various businesses in which the Pacific Improvement Company was engaged, and they are most interesting because of the picture they present of the way routine business was conducted by the holding company itself.
Among the bound volumes, the subsidiary companies must completely represented are the Carbon Hill Coal Company of Washington State, the Ione Coal and Iron Company of California, the Geary Street Park and Ocean Railway Company, the Rocky Mountain Coal and Iron Company of Wyoming, the Oakland Water Front Company, and the Southern Development Company. Those represented to a lesser extent are the San Pedro Harbor Dock and Land Company, the Capay Valley Land Company, the Union Fuel Company, Monterey County Water Works, El Verano Villa Association and El Verano Improvement Association, the Sonoma Valley Improvement Company, and the various hotels in the Monterey area and Santa Barbara.
There are several other minor groups of books but those mentioned make up the bulk of this part of the collection. The types of volumes include: By-laws, minute books, stock journals and ledgers, general journals and ledgers, cash books, checkbooks, reports, trial balances, deed registers and voucher registers. In addition, there are twenty boxes of paid out contracts and deeds of the Pacific Improvement Company and a few subsidiaries.
Maps and blueprints are included at the end of the collection, following several unidentified volumes, and many show the exact extent of the holdings of the Pacific Improvement Company in certain areas at certain times, as well as the property owned by subsidiaries.
Although some of the groups of subsidiary company books are fragmentary, on the whole the collection is quite complete and would be a valuable source to anyone interested in early California business practices or in the activities of C.P. Huntington.
Historical Note
The Pacific Improvement Company was a large holding company in California, formed during the days of C.P. Huntington, Leland Stanford, Mark Hopkins, and Charles Crocker. These men were the early controlling stockholders and directors of the company, although in this collection there is no precise indication as to the exact date of its incorporation. Two cash books, contained in the first box of the collection, are dated as early as 1869, but this is the single instance of a date this early. The greatest bulk of the collection is dated between 1883 and 1927, with scattered exceptions in the 1870's and as late as 1931.
The main activity of the company was centered in San Francisco, but between 1916 and 1919 an office in New York was active in eastern property and concerns. Names that appear throughout an extended period of years or were important in the functioning of the company are: Collis Potter Huntington, Henry Edwards Huntington, Charles Crocker (who lived only during the early years of the Pacific Improvement Company and died in 1888, but was very instrumental in the business development of California), Thomas H. Hubbard, Spencer A. Van Derveer, A.D. Shepard, S.F.B. Morse, Vanderlynn Stow, and Leon Sloss, to name just a few of the many who were connected with the vast holdings of the Pacific Improvement Company.
The company played a significant role in the development of land and railroads in various parts of the United States, but particularly in California and to a lesser extent, Texas and the southern states. C.P. Huntington was at one time president of the Southern Pacific Railroad (1890-1900) and the Pacific Improvement Company owned controlling stock in various southern railroad lines, mainly between 1880 and 1900. Land in Louisiana was also an important area of business which flourished between 1893 and 1919.
Other subsidiaries of this company included coal and iron companies, resort hotels, various California land companies and several steamships. A street railway in San Francisco was also controlled by the Pacific Improvement Company.
Provenance
Gift of W. W. Crocker to Jackson Library in 1941. Transferred to Department of Special Collections in 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- Series 1. Business and Legal Papers
  Scope and Contents note
  including documents of court action concerning the Pacific Improvement Company, correspondence directly related to them, agreements, indentures, directors' and stockholders' business, etc. The material in this series was originally grouped in the same subject arrangement that is preserved; however, there was no other arrangement originally. The subjects are grouped within the subsidiary companies to which they are connected; they are arranged by date date within subject groups.
  - PACIFIC IMPROVEMENT COMPANY
    - Cash book, (bound), 1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Loans and securities, 1880-1898 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stocks held by P.I.Co. (arranged alphabetically), 1883-1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bank books, 1906-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Associates' business, 1890-1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - List of liabilities
      - Securities loaned
      - Agreements
    - Minutes, 1915-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5a)
    - Charles Crocker's will, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Huntington suit, 1888-1904 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - George E. Spencer -vs- Arabella D. Huntington, executrix C.P. Huntington's will
    - Guatemala Central Railroad, 1878-1884 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Agreements, memoranda
    - Guatemala Central Railroad, 1885-1896 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Agreements, memoranda
    - Guatemala Central Railroad, 1882-1896 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Stock
    - Guatemala Central Railroad, 1883-1896 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence
    - Mexican International Railroad Company, 1881-1900 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence
      - Agreements
      - Stock subscriptions
    - New Orleans City and Lake Railroad Co., and New Orleans, Metarie and Lake Railroad Co., 1883-1885 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - By laws
      - Agreements
    - Miscellaneous Railroad Accounts, 1883-1898 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - St. Louis and San Francisco Ry. Co.
      - Houston and Texas Central Ry. Co.
      - San Antonio and Aransas Pass Ry. Co.
      - Indianapolis, Decatur and Western Ry. Co.
    - Southern Pacific Company, 1899-1904 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Agreements
      - Stock lists
    - Southern Development Company, 1881-1901 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Agreements
      - Deeds, leases
    - Southern Development Company, 1885-1890 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Pierce lands
    - Brown County lands, 1869-1904 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Deeds, transfer memoranda (Texas)
    - Brown County lands, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
      - Abstracts of titles
    - Brown County lands, 1875-1900 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence
    - S.H. Kneeland affairs, 1880-1886 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - White Oaks Coal lands, (New Mexico), 1883-1888 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Articles of association
      - Correspondence
    - White Oaks Coal lands, 1883-1899 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Coal land laws
      - Statement of balanced interest
    - Louisiana lands, 1883-1917 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Come Let Us Reason Together-pamphlet Agreements, deeds
    - Monterey lands, 1890-1894 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Agreement
    - San Antonio lands, 1895-1910 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Agreement
      - Schedule of lands
    - William Dorsheimer and The Star, 1885-1891 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, bills
    - William Dorsheimer and The Star, 1886-1888 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Newspaper receipts
    - William Dorsheimer and Buffalo property, 1886-1890 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Summons and complaints
      - Agreements
    - William Dorsheimer and Buffalo property, 1887-1899 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence
    - Richard Derby deeds to Thomas H. Hubbard, 1900-1905 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous land accounts, 1898-1900 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Deferred payments on land sales
    - Steamships, (El Paso, El Dorado, El Monte, Eureka), 1881-1890 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Building contracts, bills of sale
    - Steamships, (Pier 37, San Pablo, El Mar, San Mateo, El Sol, El Norte, El Sud), 1883-1892 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Building contracts
    - Steamships, (El Rio, El Cid, Mineola, Chalmette), 1890-1896 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Building contracts
    - Detroit Gas Company, 1883-1896 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Reports, statements
    - Detroit Gas Company, 1893-1899 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Correspondence
    - Detroit Gas Company, 1894-1898 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Coupon receipts
    - Natural Gas and Oil Company of Ontario, and United Gas and Oil Co. of Ontario, 1899-1904 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Agreements, property lists, stock
    - Speyer and Company, 1896-1897 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - City of Clarksdale -vs- P.I.Co., 1889-1898 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Contracts (Mississippi)
      - Appeals, bills of complaint
    - City of Clarksdale -vs- P.I.Co., 1894-1911 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence
    - City of Clarksdale -vs- P.I.Co., 1898 (Box 6, Folder 44)
      - Address of the Committee on the Articles of Agreement creating the Clarksdale
      - Improvement Company
      - Printed transcripts of record
    - P.I.Co. -vs- City of Clarksdale, [1895?] (Box 6, Folder 45)
      - Printed transcripts
    - Atlantic Mutual Insurance Company, 1886-1894 (Box 6, Folder 46)
      - Vessel cargo
    - Miscellaneous Business, 1885-1910 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - Papers from drawer in safe
    - Texas, Telephone and Telegraph Co., 1890-1910 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Oregon Property-F.H. Davis, 1894-1906 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Ocos Railroad Co., 1910 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Guatemala Central RR Co., 1895-1913 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Chattanooga Southern RR, 1897-1914 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Tennessee, Alabama, and Georgia RR, 1907-1917 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - FINANCIAL IMPROVEMENT COMPANY
    - Agreements, 1882-1884 (Box 8, Folder 54)
      - Incorporation 1882
    - Minutes, 1882-1894 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Agreements, 1892-1893 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - First Mortgage Bonds, 1882-1885 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Stockholders Meetings, 1882-1893 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Miscellaneous deeds, transactions, 1887-1895 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence, 1892-1899 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - MISSISSIPPI VALLEY CONSTRUCTION COMPANY
    - Business papers, 1882-1890 (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - Mississippi River Improvement and Levee Convention, 1890
      - Agreement: Board of Levee Commissioners By laws
    - Minute book, (bound), 1882-1906 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - SAN ANTONIO LAND COMPANY
    - Financial business, 1886-1898 (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - Trial balances
      - Receipts and disbursements
    - Stockholders' meetings, 1886-1899 (Box 9, Folder 64)
    - Cash book, (bound), 1886-1901 (Box 9, Folder 65)
    - Record book, (bound), 1887-1898 (Box 9, Folder 66)
    - Check book (Lone Star Land Co.), 1883-1893 (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Record book (Lone Star Land Co.), 1883-1893 (Box 10, Folder 68)
      - Articles of incorporation
      - By laws
      - Minutes
  - MISSISSIPPI VALLEY SHIP ISLAND RAILROAD COMPANY
    - Meetings of incorporators, 1871-1882 (Box 10, Folder 69)
      - Directors' meeting, 1873
      - Mortgages
    - State of Mississippi -vs- Mississippi Valley Ship Island RR Co., 1873-1882 (Box 10, Folder 70)
      - Injunctions
      - Legal documents
    - Newspaper notices, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - Miscellaneous business, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 72)
      - Board of Mayor and Aldermen of Port
      - Gibson -vs- Miss. Valley S.I. RR Co.
      - Railway bonds list
      - Statement of assets
      - Letters
  - MISSISSIPPI AND TENNESSEE RAILROAD COMPANY
    - Stockholders, 1877-1886 (Box 10, Folder 73)
      - Reports, 1880, 1883, 1884, 1885
      - Mortgage
    - Moore -vs- Mississippi and Tennessee RR Co., 1884-1886 (Box 10, Folder 74)
      - Exhibits, answers
    - Hearkness -vs- Mississippi and Tennessee RR Co., 1884-1886 (Box 10, Folder 75)
      - Correspondence
  - LOUISVILLE, NEW ORLEANS, AND TEXAS RAILWAY COMPANY
    - Correspondence: C.P. Huntington and Homes Cummins, 1881-1882 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - New Orleans and Mississippi Valley Railroad Company (before consolidation with LNOT), 1881-1884 (Box 10, Folder 77)
      - Act of incorporation, 1881
      - Resolutions on consolidation, 1884
    - Newspaper notices on consolidation, 1882-1886 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - Agreements, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 79-80)
      - Consolidation groundwork
      - Eugene Martin and Wm. M. Johnston R.T. Wilson and C.P. Huntington
    - Agreements, 1884-1886 (Box 11, Folder 81-82)
    - Consolidation (Box 11, Folder 81-82)
      - Johnston and Martin
      - City of Vicksburg
      - Railroad agreements
    - Correspondence, 1882-1886 (Box 11, Folder 83)
      - Concerning consolidation
    - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 11, Folder 84)
      - Concerning use of Mississippi and Tennessee terminal facilities
    - Correspondence, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 85)
      - Concerning New Orleans Belt railroad
    - Jackson land in Louisiana, 1881-1885 (Box 11, Folder 86)
      - Agreements, deeds
      - Abstract of title
      - Payments
    - Land sales and disputes, 1882-1889 (Box 11, Folder 87)
      - Notes, figures
      - Statements, lists of sales
    - Baton Rouge Barracks, 1884-1886 (Box 11, Folder 88)
      - Act to reroute LNOT and move barracks
      - Correspondence
    - Mortgage bonds, 1884-1886 (Box 12, Folder 89)
      - Deeds, memoranda
      - Agreements, Crolius and Pardee
    - Mortgage bonds, pamphlets, no dates (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - Mortgage bonds, 1885-1889 (Box 12, Folder 91)
      - Resolutions on mortgages
      - Receipts for bonds
    - Disbursements, 1885-1892 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - Distribution of securities, 1883-1894 (Box 12, Folder 93)
      - Misc. correspondence
      - Hobart and Smith securities claim, 1883-1886
    - Letters of resignation, 1879-1882 (Box 12, Folder 94)
      - To the railroad companies consolidating with the LNOT Ry Co.
    - Stocks and stockholders, 1884 and 1886 (Box 12, Folder 95)
      - Of the railroad companies consolidating with the LNOT Ry Co.
    - Resolutions of stockholders, directors, 1888 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - Acts and Authorities, 1881-1888 (Box 12, Folder 97)
      - Senate bills
      - State laws
    - Union Improvement Company and Northwestern Improvement Company, 1888-1900 (Box 12, Folder 98)
      - By laws
      - Correspondence
    - Natchez, Jackson and Columbus Railroad Company, 1889-1890 (Box 12, Folder 99)
      - Sale to LNOT
      - Documents, agreements
      - By laws
    - Natchez, Jackson and Columbus RR Co., 1889-1899 (Box 13, Folder 100)
      - Correspondence re: sale to LNOT
    - Natchez, Jackson and Columbus RR Co., 1900 (Box 13, Folder 101)
      - Hinds County -vs- Natchez, Jackson and Columbus RR Co.
      - Original bill, correspondence
    - Mobile and Northwestern Railroad Co., 1889-1892 (Box 13, Folder 102)
      - Indenture
      - Sale to LNOT
    - Memphis and New Orleans RR and Levee Co., 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 103)
      - Sale to LNOT
      - Act of consolidation
      - Deeds, indentures
    - Memphis and New Orleans RR and Levee Co., 1887 (Box 13, Folder 104)
      - Newspaper notices of sale
    - Court suits, 1880-1884 (Box 13, Folder 105)
      - Louisiana Nat'l Bank -vs- LNOT
      - R.T. Wilson -vs- East Tennessee, Virginia and Georgia Railroad Co.
    - Court suits, 1885-1889 (Box 13, Folder 106)
      - Nat'l Park Bank of New York -vs- George M. Klein
      - Tax suit
    - Court suits, 1886-1892 (Box 13, Folder 107)
      - Allen and Stead
      - Louisville Nashville
      - Lewiston Mills
      - LNOT -vs- G.Y. Scott et al
      - Ford and Levy -vs- LNOT
    - Court suits, 1886-1892 (Box 13, Folder 108)
      - Bonelli
      - R.T. Wilson -vs- West Feliciana Railroad
      - LNOT -vs- State of Mississippi
      - LNOT -vs- J.A. Payne, guardian
    - Cotton suits, 1889 (Box 13, Folder 109)
      - Newspaper clippings
    - Richard T. Wilson -vs- Bank of New York et al, 1886-1887 (Box 13, Folder 110)
      - Affidavits, notices of trial
    - First National Bank of Wilmington -vs- R.T. Wilson, (Delaware), 1884-1899 (Box 14, Folder 111-112)
      - Briefs
    - First Nat'l Bank of Wilmington -vs- Wilson, 1887 (Box 14, Folder 113)
      - Correspondence
    - Whitney -vs- Harris, 1875-1885 (Box 14, Folder 114)
      - Affidavits, orders, decrees
    - Whitney -vs- Harris, 1894-1900 (Box 14, Folder 115)
      - Affidavits, memoranda
    - Whitney -vs- Harris, 1885-1895 (Box 14, Folder 116)
      - Correspondence
    - Whitney -vs- Harris, 1898-1904 (Box 14, Folder 117)
      - Correspondence
    - William P. Hunt -vs- LNOT, 1882-1888 (Box 14, Folder 118)
      - Affidavits, bills, answers, agreements
    - Hunt -vs- LNOT, 1889-1891 (Box 15, Folder 119)
      - Affidavits, bills, answers, agreements
    - Hunt -vs- LNOT, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 120)
      - Depositions
    - Hunt -vs- LNOT, 1891-1892 (Box 15, Folder 121)
      - Affidavits, bills, answers, agreements
      - Miscellaneous notes
    - Keuduskeag National Bank -vs- Wm. P. Hunt, 1891-1892 (Box 15, Folder 122)
      - Agreements
      - Promissory notes
    - Hunt: Examinations in insolvency, 1889-1890 (Box 15, Folder 123)
    - James H. Young -vs- Wm. P. Hunt, [1889?] (Box 15, Folder 124)
      - Bills of complaint, answers
    - Young: Correspondence, 1887-1889 (Box 15, Folder 125)
    - Young: Correspondence, 1890-1891 (Box 15, Folder 126)
    - Young: Correspondence, 1891-1893 (Box 16, Folder 127)
    - Amos Woodruff -vs- State of Mississippi and LNOT et al, 1889-1895 (Box 16, Folder 128)
      - Briefs, bills
      - Newspaper clippings
    - Woodruff -vs- State of Mississippi and LNOT et al, 1890-1900 (Box 16, Folder 129)
      - Correspondence
    - City of Vicksburg -vs- LNOT, 1872-1885 (Box 16, Folder 130)
      - Bills
      - Newspaper notices
    - Eugene Martin -vs- Memphis and Vicksburg Railroad Co., 1883-1885 (Box 16, Folder 131)
      - Legal documents
    - Martin -vs- Memphis and Vicksburg RR Co., 1885-1888 (Box 16, Folder 132)
      - Legal Documents
    - Martin -vs- Memphis and Vicksburg RR Co., 1888-1904 (Box 17, Folder 133)
      - Legal Documents
    - Martin -vs- Memphis and Vicksburg RR Co., no date (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - Printed transcript of record
    - Martin court suits, 1884-1904 (Box 17, Folder 135)
      - Wm. Johnston -vs- Martin
      - Martin -vs- Pardee and Croliu
      - Martin -vs- R.T. Wilson
    - Martin court suits, 1883-1910 (Box 17, Folder 136)
      - Correspondence
    - Mineral trust, 1887-1893 (Box 17, Folder 137)
      - Documents
      - Correspondence
    - Friar's Point and Fischer and Burnett (Box 17, Folder 138)
    - Lumber Company, (Tennessee), 1889-1896
      - Correspondence
      - Statements, land notes
    - Southwest Virginia Land and Cattle Co. (Box 17, Folder 139)
    - and Stuart Land and Cattle Co., 1884-1887
      - Charters
      - By laws
    - Correspondence, 1882-1883 (Box 18, Folder 140)
    - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 141)
    - Correspondence, 1884 (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 18, Folder 143)
    - Correspondence, 1885 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 18, Folder 145)
    - Correspondence, 1886 (Box 19, Folder 146)
    - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 19, Folder 147)
    - Correspondence, 1887 (Box 19, Folder 148)
    - Correspondence, 1888 (Box 19, Folder 149)
    - Correspondence, 1889 (Box 19, Folder 150)
    - Correspondence, 1890-1900 (Box 19, Folder 151)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (June-July) (Box 20, Folder 152)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (August-Sept.) (Box 20, Folder 153)
    - Correspondence, 1895 (Oct.-Dec.) (Box 20, Folder 154)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (Jan.-Mar.) (Box 20, Folder 155)
    - Correspondence, 1896 (April-July) (Box 20, Folder 156)
    - Bills Receivable Book (bound), 1885-1891 (Box 21)
  - ILLINOIS CENTRAL RAILROAD COMPANY
    - Agreements and indentures, 1892 (Box 22, Folder 157-158)
      - Regarding purchase of the LNOT Ry Co.
      - stocks and bonds
    - Correspondence, 1892-1894 (Box 22, Folder 159)
      - Regarding purchase of the LNOT
    - Correspondence, 1893-1894 (Box 22, Folder 160)
    - Bonds, 1892 (Box 22, Folder 161)
      - Interim certificates
      - Assets and liabilities of the LNOT
  - YAZOO AND MISSISSIPPI VALLEY RAILROAD CO.
    - Consolidation agreements, 1892 (Box 22, Folder 162)
    - Tax suit, 1893-1900 (Box 22, Folder 163)
      - Yazoo and Miss. Valley RR Co. -vs- Wirt Adams, State Revenue agent
      - Briefs
      - Correspondence
      - Pamphlet: History of the LNOT Ry Co.
    - Tax suit, 1896 (Box 23, Folder 164)
      - Printed brief
    - Correspondence, 1900 (Box 23, Folder 165)
      - Land matters
      - Deed disputes
  - GEARY STREET PARK AND OCEAN RAILWAY CO.
    - Castle Crags, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 166)
      - Finances
    - Meeting notices, 1878-1917 (Box 23, Folder 167)
      - List of records
      - By laws
    - Stockholders, 1913-1914 (Box 23, Folder 168)
      - Investigation reports
    - Stocks and bonds, 1880-1916 (Box 23, Folder 169)
      - Charts
    - Legal matters, 1891-1910 (Box 23, Folder 170)
    - Legal Matters, 1911-1917 (Box 23, Folder 171)
    - General Correspondence, 1903-1916 (Box 23, Folder 172)
    - Property and financial matters, 1910-1919 (Box 23, Folder 173)
      - Statements
      - Charts of property owned by Geary St.
      - P. O. Ry Co.
  - OAKLAND WATER FRONT COMPANY
    - A.D. Wilson -vs- Oakland Water Front Co., no dates (Box 24, Folder 174)
      - Photographs, maps
    - Wilson -vs- OWFCo, 1915-1917 (Box 24, Folder 175)
      - Legal documents
    - Wilson -vs- OWFCo, 1917-? (Box 24, Folder 176)
      - Legal documents